<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musings on Witty Writeups</title>
    <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/categories/musings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Musings on Witty Writeups</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 16:31:16 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jeansung.github.io/blog/categories/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on College Graduation</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/college-grad-reflections/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 16:31:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/college-grad-reflections/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The only books I read (anymore)</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/good-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 18:19:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/good-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to read a lot. I grew up reading lots of books from fantasy (all of Harry Potter like many) to cheesy teen romance novels. I even read a book once (okay the entire series) that was written in the style of an IM conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In high school I read the classics - To Kill a Mockingbird, Catch-22, Hamlet, for English, which I liked but only because we had to analyze “deeper meaning” and that was more fun than I knew it could be (but that’s a story for another time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not so much recently. I have to read textbooks during the year - so Physical Chemistry, Linear Algebra and Operating Systems when school is in session. But not really during breaks or for fun. I read articles online and magazines on plane and yes, I guess that does count as reading. But there is something about reading good old fashioned book that I just haven’t done in what seems like forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I got a chance to kickstart the reading habit this summer because of my 40 minute commute (well it’s an hour back in rush hours) by bus. And S let me borrow her old nook. And the library has free e books to rent. Anyways, it came together. And I now remember the only books I can get through anymore fall into 3 categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cheesy teen romance novels&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;That’s how I got through the 40 minutes on the light rail to the airport&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Books about time management, organization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;My not so secret obsession&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Books that fall under the “common misconception” category See below&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The last category is interesting because it’s my favorite category. I tell people my favorite book is Catch - 22 which is true but it’s not the type of book I like to read. I like to read books that are stories. Stories about how the way we think is intuitive, which is wrong. These are books that I like to think are born of the Common misconceptions page on Wikipedia.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two such series which I have read and loved are Freakanomics (I’m on the third one) and Malcom Galdwell’s books (all of them). I like them because they are good stories. Stories about how looking at things from a different angle often yields an interesting and meaningful response. And stories about how math is important. And data. And the difference between correlation and causation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>