<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Witty Writeups</title>
    <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Witty Writeups</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 14:54:38 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jeansung.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Planning Planners: A 4 year journey </title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/planner_story/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 14:54:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/planner_story/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This post is kind of long. So here&amp;rsquo;s a mini table of contents up front. It&amp;rsquo;s about my 4 year journey and work in finding a good planner system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents:7ba532dc6e93af68996c1e3cf37a03b9&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-this-post-is&#34;&gt;What this post is&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#what-i&#39;ve-tried&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve tried&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#factors-to-consider&#34;&gt;Factors to Consider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#things-i-need-to-track&#34;&gt;Things I Need to Track&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#plan&#34;&gt;Plan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction:7ba532dc6e93af68996c1e3cf37a03b9&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a lot of research for this post. Shoutout to all the girls on tumblr and youtube who&amp;rsquo;s life is perfect and together. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jeansung.github.io/blog/planner_pics/perfect1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://jeansung.github.io/blog/planner_pics/perfect2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://jeansung.github.io/blog/planner_pics/perfect3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially their handwriting. One of my best friends has perfect handwriting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jeansung.github.io/blog/planner_pics/paula.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should just hire her to write all my crap down. Her handwriting is literally so perfect it could be its own font. Mine&amp;rsquo;s okay when I try and kinda gross when I don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-this-post-is:7ba532dc6e93af68996c1e3cf37a03b9&#34;&gt;What this post is&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a good way of keeping track of my shit in high school, specifically my homework. That&amp;rsquo;s almost all I had in high school. We got a school agenda, and six lines a day was enough to capture the homework/stuff I had to do, bless my heart. This is partly a chronology of my journey through college. I had a hard time replicating my set up in high school because there has been so much more to do and thus so much more to keep track of. Especially more homework. But it&amp;rsquo;s more than that- there are school events, and whole days where I&amp;rsquo;m book sun up to sun down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And with all that, I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to nail down a consistent way to actually track everything in my 4 years. And since it&amp;rsquo;s my last semester this spring (graduating May 15th!!), I figure I&amp;rsquo;d give it one last shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-i-ve-tried:7ba532dc6e93af68996c1e3cf37a03b9&#34;&gt;What I&amp;rsquo;ve tried&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of what I have tried so far. For each method, there&amp;rsquo;s a description, when I used it and some pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;google-calendar-gtask:7ba532dc6e93af68996c1e3cf37a03b9&#34;&gt;Google Calendar + gTask&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this during Fall 2014 and I think intermittently in the semester before. Google calendar is pretty standard fare, just having events and recurring classes, etc. gTask is a google calendar add on task manager where you can add tasks onto the same interface as google calendar. You can add homework, chores, etc in the slot where the day events normally go. Here is an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jeansung.github.io/blog/planner_pics/gtask.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good: You can put everything in one place, which is nice because that means you only have to check one thing in the morning. That’s nice. Also, I used a phone app that let you see things on the google and do recurring tasks (like for problem sets due every week or laundry, which happens on Fridays).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bad: As you can see in the picture - lots of tasks + lots of events (aka my life) makes things hard to see. I did get a 27 inch monitor that semester so it was easier to see on the big screen, but it’s not anywhere else. It’s way too cramped. Also, recurring events was just a phone app thing which meant you couldn’t make new ones on the computer. That was kinda annoying and reduced how useable it was.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;todoist:7ba532dc6e93af68996c1e3cf37a03b9&#34;&gt;Todoist&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this primarily during Fall 2015 and mostly during the second half. The idea with this tool is that you write down what you need to get done and it acts as a dynamic check lists. It is a place to collect homework (e.g. recurring problem sets), due dates, checklists of chores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jeansung.github.io/blog/planner_pics/todoist.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good: You can do recurring events pretty easily. And the built in syntax is pretty nice to capture due dates easily from English. Also there’s a million apps for it. You can do desktop app, website, tablet, and phone app. But I will say I never really looked at the phone app. You get a productivity score which can be fun if you care (I don’t). Plus, you can look at what you have to do for the next 7 days, which is pretty handy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bad: It’s hard to do exceptions. Like recurring events except for this week and that other week. The big thing is that it is impossible in this system to make a distinction between when something is due and when you are planning to work on it. For example, when homework is due on Friday, I will probably start on Monday, and try to attend office hours during the week and work on it a lot Wednesday and Thursday. With this system it&amp;rsquo;s just a list of due dates, so there is no way to easily capture something that&amp;rsquo;s in progress. Or map out when I am doing what homework.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;moleskine-paper-planner:7ba532dc6e93af68996c1e3cf37a03b9&#34;&gt;Moleskine paper planner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this all semester for Spring 2015 and tried to and failed to use this for Fall 2015. I wrote down homework due dates and exam dates. As well as special events dates. It is similar to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.moleskine.com/en/collections/model/product/12-months-weekly-notebook-black-soft-cover-large&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jeansung.github.io/blog/planner_pics/moleskine1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://jeansung.github.io/blog/planner_pics/moleskine2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good: When it works it’s the greatest. I loved this so much. It can be so pretty. You can use colors to do color coding. I added stickers and washi tape and some weeks are absolutely instagram worthy (not pictured above- these weeks were messy and busy, a more accurate characterization of my time at Mudd).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bad: When the homework spills over or when things change so often it gets messy. For example, exam dates, which are usually set at the beginning of the semester might change. Meetings change. Homework sometimes even changes. Not being able to adjust to that change means really messy week views and hard to use planner - that will drive me to do something else. Also, some weeks are just too busy for this planner. You can already see that in the dead week pictures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cheap-office-max-paper-planner-at-a-glance-8-5x11:7ba532dc6e93af68996c1e3cf37a03b9&#34;&gt;Cheap Office Max Paper Planner - At A Glance 8.5x11&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used this for September in my freshman year - so Fall 2012. And then I just had too much homework and events for this so I just switched back to google calendar. Freshman year. That was a really long time ago. I don’t have much else to say for this because I distinctly remember using it for all of 2 or 3 weeks.
One piece of paper a week&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;one-piece-of-paper-week:7ba532dc6e93af68996c1e3cf37a03b9&#34;&gt;One piece of paper / week&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve tried this method twice. Once in the fall of my sophomore year (so fall 2013) and once for the beginning of my senior year (fall 2015). This is a good method because it is not a long term commitment because when you mess up, you can just move onto the next week. However, I do like having more things together. It&amp;rsquo;s also surprisingly difficult to find a good place for a piece of paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://jeansung.github.io/blog/planner_pics/weeklytemplate_v1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;factors-to-consider:7ba532dc6e93af68996c1e3cf37a03b9&#34;&gt;Factors to consider&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Electronic versus paper&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paper is good because it is just prettier. See the above for a small sample of aesthetics you can achieve with paper. I just don&amp;rsquo;t see the sample level of customization with electronic tools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paper can be harder to correct and adjust when things change - how do you write down stuff for months later. Or how do you make a change to an event that&amp;rsquo;s changing location or some other details. (For this, I&amp;rsquo;ve actually learned that you can write stuff down on stickies and then later write it in).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, preset paper planners tend to come with varying amounts of extra cruft that I don&amp;rsquo;t need and can be hard to get rid of - pages for phone numbers, important birthdays, lots of extra junk. I hate this because I won&amp;rsquo;t take the time to replicate it. I know just the basic birthdays (close friends and family) and that&amp;rsquo;s all I really care about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;What if things don&amp;rsquo;t fit on the paper? I know I need at least a 5x8, preferably bigger, but with whatever size I get some weeks are sorta hell anyways.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have the material and I keep buying stuff to make it pretty - washi tape, index cards, stickers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Electronic is better because you can do recurring events easier - you don&amp;rsquo;t have to keep writing - like laundry and back ups happens every week. But the interface for electronics has never been that impressive it always feels clunky.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;With electronics there&amp;rsquo;s a pipe dream that it might let you do everything together - events and to dos and due dates. This would be nice because then there are less things to check. I have yet to find this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Specifically for paper planners, whether it is pre decorated (aka store bought) or bare (fully customized from a notebook or similar). The benefit of having a predecorated one is that it just looks nice and gives you some place to start for decorating it. However, bare planners can look really nice, but only if you have the right handwriting and decorating time and skills (I have neither).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Portability - is it small enough to take with me when I need it. For this criteria, I was originally learning towards electronics for this one because I always have my phone on me even when I don&amp;rsquo;t have my computer, but I actually don&amp;rsquo;t take out my phone in class to write down something important like this. Some professors don&amp;rsquo;t like when you take out your phone and it&amp;rsquo;s disruptive to me paying attention for notes otherwise. Thus, it inevitably gets written down physically. Earlier, I was also concerned with portability when I go out with people. However, this is a good work life balance lesson for me. The only time I should be using this is in class, or doing homework; both times I should have my planner + accessories. Otherwise, I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t worry about this during social times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;things-i-need-to-track:7ba532dc6e93af68996c1e3cf37a03b9&#34;&gt;Things I need to track&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;events - appointments, classes, events on campus, talks I want to go to, lunches that I agree to have with people. The best way to characterize this category is events where my time is explicitly blocked out. Because of shared events, etc, this has to go in google calendar. Plus I like knowing where I am needed and when on a daily basis. Google Calendar is a solution that I have known and loved for this.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;homework and other recurring tasks like chores, these usually happen on the same day every week&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;one off big tasks - like exams or other important due dates like term papers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;one off small tasks  that I think of - go to target, or finishing grading X by this Friday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;ongoing thoughts - like a collection of thoughts for my blog post. I hate keeping this on my computer because it just sits there and I have it in like 5 different places. Plus, I think these are more thoughtful if I write them out. These also include more longer term to dos that don&amp;rsquo;t have a specific timeline attached to it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;plan:7ba532dc6e93af68996c1e3cf37a03b9&#34;&gt;Plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to use 3 things to keep me organized this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;| Tool | Content |
|:&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;|:&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;|
| Planner | Some appointments - like special occasions and lunches. Homework, Exams. |
| Google Calendar | Regular recurring events like classes, and appointments. |
| Common Place Book | Ongoing thoughts and ideas. |&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Tools&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Review&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Planner&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Some appointments - like special occasions and lunches. Homework, Exams.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;a&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the planner, I ended up going with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B011PBKWG4?psc=1&amp;amp;redirect=true&amp;amp;ref_=od_aui_detailpages00&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. For the paper planner, I&amp;rsquo;m using stickers, and washi tape. I plan to use the notes section on the bottom for exercise, to help myself track my daily activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s my plan for how to use the planner. At the beginning of the semester, I will compile a list of chores (gym days, vacuum, laundry (regular, bedding), backup, dishes, planning, budget (?)). Then, at the end of each week (on Friday), I will take time out of my week and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;decorate the weekly spread with washi tape and small stickers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using stickies to take temp dates in the future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will update this post with my month, 3 month and 6 months progress update on what the weekly spreads look like and how I&amp;rsquo;m going.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Okay to Cry: 15 Things I Learned My Senior Fall</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/fall2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 20:19:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/fall2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to cry. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to cry every Tuesday at noon for 20 minutes before big algs. It&amp;rsquo;s not because of big algs, but it was just the only time I had all week. I mean I already knew this from many semesters ago, but I think I must have forgotten this from the last couple of semesters. School can be hard, when you&amp;rsquo;re taking clinic, ai, PLs, and big algs. Plus a hum, plus grading and tutoring. And extracurriculars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure you check in with a friend who knows what you are up to. Maybe tell your suite mate. Talk to the school psychologist. Make sure it&amp;rsquo;s not too awful.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;But you can ignore certain advice. If someone is telling you to drop a certain class and its the only you love right now, it&amp;rsquo;s okay to push back.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;But you should be choosy about what you want to do - you don&amp;rsquo;t have to agree to do everything that comes your way. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t. Research, job interview offers, it&amp;rsquo;s okay to be picky. Don&amp;rsquo;t use the fear of missing out and try to do everything. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t work that way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also okay to drop things. I started the semester with 3 jobs, a lot of extra extracurriculars and free time. I cut down to one primary extracurricular activity and just one tutoring/grading job. I felt bad I couldn&amp;rsquo;t do everything, but I was just too busy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to be bitter. There&amp;rsquo;s not too much to say about this. Very bitter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;But remember why you chose the school in the first place. It is still worth it even if you can&amp;rsquo;t remember that in the present. It is. At least for me. Big algs is your favorite, even if your favorite is problematic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to get used a new normal. Rounded corners on your proofs, and working on homework the same day it&amp;rsquo;s due. Not getting enough sleep going into Monday. Working on PLs 6 hours before it&amp;rsquo;s due. You didn&amp;rsquo;t used to do this. You used to be so on top of things. It&amp;rsquo;s okay. Do what you need to do to survive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Know what is more productive. Don&amp;rsquo;t spend half an hour on the homework when you could better to use the time to do something else. Like taking a shower, or eating breakfast. That makes a difference. It really does. Try it. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to take time to take care of yourself. You can do well on your homework still.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take breaks. Real breaks where you go rock climbing and leave campus. Or leave the city and go into the fair. You can afford it, time wise. Well, you can&amp;rsquo;t, but you should go anyways and suffer later with homework. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, you&amp;rsquo;ll shrivel up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pick a new light at the end of the tunnel. Maybe you have committed to getting a job at the end of the semester and then you can use that to help you get through. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s an iphone wallpaper that says &amp;ldquo;when life gets tough, get tougher.&amp;rdquo; Even if it&amp;rsquo;s a lie, use it. Believe in the lie to make it to the end. Know that it is is temporary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take your high school accomplishments off your resume. Seriously, it&amp;rsquo;s just unprofessional and desperate. Nobody is impressed. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, you were valedictorian. But so was half your graduating class.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is no shame is wearing your hair in the messiest of buns and having sweatpants on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be nice to other people after you&amp;rsquo;re done with something. Have empathy once you&amp;rsquo;ve picked a job, and once you&amp;rsquo;ve finished finals. This semester doesn&amp;rsquo;t just suck for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2015: Books</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/summer-2015-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 21:52:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/summer-2015-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At long last, here is the final count of the books that I managed to read over the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Author&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Review&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9627755-isla-and-the-happily-ever-after&#34;&gt;Isla and the Happily Ever After&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Stephanie Perkins&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a classic chick lit novel, the kind I use to read in high school but it was good. It was a good page turner and I got through it quickly, on a train and a plane.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gladwell.com/david-and-goliath/&#34;&gt;David and Goliath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;A new book by one of my favorite authors. This was an excellent read. It&amp;rsquo;s another one of those books that weaves together stories you don&amp;rsquo;t hear about into patterns that don&amp;rsquo;t seem intuitive until they are. It&amp;rsquo;s cleverly woven together, backed by math and logic. I love these books. Also checkout his &lt;a href=&#34;http://gladwell.com/&#34;&gt;other books&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://freakonomics.com/2014/04/02/think-like-a-freak-our-new-book-out-on-may-13/&#34;&gt;Think Like A Freak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Steven D. Levitt, Stephen J. Dubner&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Basically same review as above. I wish I could find more books like these. These are my favorite kind of books. Also checkout the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freakonomics&#34;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SuperFreakonomics&#34;&gt;second&lt;/a&gt; in the trilogy. I&amp;rsquo;m sad they won&amp;rsquo;t be writing anymore of these.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/2014/07/26/334038029/lessons-in-essentialism-getting-more-out-of-life-by-doing-less&#34;&gt;Essentialism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting into this trend recently. Reading a lot of articles online during my lunch break. It&amp;rsquo;s a good read and it was fun to indulge myself before I go back to school where it&amp;rsquo;s less like essentialism and more like &amp;ldquo;do everything ism&amp;rdquo;. Ah, college.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sophiekinsella.co.uk/book_detail.php?b=7&#34;&gt;Shopaholic to the Stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sophia Kinsella&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I really only read this because I&amp;rsquo;ve read the previous god knows how many books (7th!!) in this series. It&amp;rsquo;s sort of trashy and sort of cheap, but it&amp;rsquo;s a very quick read.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theghostmap.com/&#34;&gt;The Ghost Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Steven Johnson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I love this story. I did a presentation on the development of the sewage system in London and the 1848 Cholera outbreak. It was an indepth look at all aspects of the disease from more angles than I thought possible. &lt;strong&gt;Definitely&lt;/strong&gt; worth it. It was so great.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16143347-we-were-liars&#34;&gt;We Were Liars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;E. Lockhart&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;It was a good read. A page turner, and a good book that was aimed at my demographic, for once. It was half a teen romance and half a teen family drama. The mystery in the pages really help keep it going. I got through this book on a train and a plane. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely a enthralling read.  However, retrospectively, I guess I have to agree with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/11/books/review/we-were-liars-by-e-lockhart.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;New York Times Review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gettingthingsdone.com/&#34;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;David Allen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ve read this before. It&amp;rsquo;s good, and I like organizational books, but the system is a bit complex and I think it would work better with a consistent work schedule rather than a busy and every shifting school schedule. People say to treat your job like a 9-5 but my job is more like a 10am-12am. Or something like that. Ahh, clinic.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;GRE Math, Verbal prep&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kaplan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;This is because I decided for some reason it would be a good idea to sign up for and then study for and then take the August GRE. Oh silly me. It was fine. Just a long test. Luckily, I remembered most of my middle school and high school math. Shame there&amp;rsquo;s no calculus.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Google Forms to Budget</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/google-form-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 08:30:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/google-form-budget/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h4 id=&#34;before-the-summer:ff2dc01f53c5092c45e82cd6a8ccdc4a&#34;&gt;Before the summer&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the background for this is that I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Excel to budget my summer spending since the summer after high school. A lot has changed since then. Back in Summer 2012, I spent less than $1000 for the entire summer, lived at home and worked 7 hours / week at a minimum wage job. This summer, I&amp;rsquo;m living with friends in Seattle, working full time at an internship, spending about $4000 for the summer. I used to spend money by my parents credit card and cash. Now I have my own credit card. I pay rent and buy groceries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Then:&lt;/strong&gt; Excel or other tsv, tracked by week
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Now:&lt;/strong&gt; Google Forms and Google spreadsheet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;summer-setup:ff2dc01f53c5092c45e82cd6a8ccdc4a&#34;&gt;Summer setup&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created a google form to track my expenses. I would gather all the relevant information that I thought was necessary. See below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/hiZ0hd3.png =516x140&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/XivL2Nc.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I do: After I spend money, I collect my receipts and enter in the information into the form and submit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;feedback:ff2dc01f53c5092c45e82cd6a8ccdc4a&#34;&gt;Feedback&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good: It&amp;rsquo;s uniform and I can capture information in a way that makes sense to me. I have tried using online categories before and having a lot of preset values makes it difficult to see what I actually am spending in categories that matter to me. It was really easy to set up, and Google Forms have a good summary view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bad: It&amp;rsquo;s really hard, actually impossible to change the values you enter after you leave the form- if something gets messed up, there is no way to delete the data from the form entries. That makes the summary view useless because you can&amp;rsquo;t erase mistaken values. Additionally, the summary view is not customizable. Plus, there is a lot of work to do per transaction, especially since most of my spending is done by credit card these days. It would be nice if I could do the set up just once and then just track remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next: For the fall, I am try using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mint.com/&#34;&gt;Mint&lt;/a&gt;. Stay tuned for a review on that!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Hugo Website Setup</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/hugo-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 22:01:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/hugo-setup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-started:64a00e54bc112d22b252689389accbce&#34;&gt;Getting Started&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was lured to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; because of its pretty front end on the main website and the promise that I could develop in Markdown. I have 3 websites, my &lt;a href=&#34;http://jeansung.github.io/frontpage/&#34;&gt;front page&lt;/a&gt;, my &lt;a href=&#34;http://jeansung.github.io/blog/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; and my &lt;a href=&#34;http://jeansung.github.io/Projects/&#34;&gt;portfolio&lt;/a&gt; and the first two are setup through hugo. Here&amp;rsquo;s my setup story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-setup:64a00e54bc112d22b252689389accbce&#34;&gt;My setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m hosting it on github pages. Here&amp;rsquo;s my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jeansung/MyPersonalPage/wiki&#34;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; how to set that up. I&amp;rsquo;m using hugo with github pages. Here&amp;rsquo;s the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/&#34;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt; I used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I test my changes, I run the command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server --watch --buildDrafts --theme=material-design
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This command runs a local server for the website to sit on, build drafts, automatically reloads pages and then applies the theme. You can delete the &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; folder to force the theme to reload completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m ready to publish, I use a modified version of the tutorial&amp;rsquo;s demo &lt;code&gt;deploy.sh&lt;/code&gt; script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#!/bin/bash

# Black        0;30     Dark Gray     1;30
# Red          0;31     Light Red     1;31
# Green        0;32     Light Green   1;32
# Brown/Orange 0;33     Yellow        1;33
# Blue         0;34     Light Blue    1;34
# Purple       0;35     Light Purple  1;35
# Cyan         0;36     Light Cyan    1;36
# Light Gray   0;37     White         1;37

CYAN=&#39;\033[0;36m&#39;
NC=&#39;\033[0m&#39;

echo -e &amp;quot;${CYAN} Deploying updates to GitHub... ${NC}&amp;quot;


# Build the project. 
hugo --theme material-design

# Add changes to git.
git add -A

# Commit changes.
msg=&amp;quot;Rebuilding site `date`&amp;quot;
if [ $# -eq 1 ]
  then msg=&amp;quot;$1&amp;quot;
fi
git commit -m &amp;quot;$msg&amp;quot;

# Push source and build repos.
git push origin master
git subtree push --prefix=public git@github.com:jeansung/blog.git gh-pages
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-thoughts:64a00e54bc112d22b252689389accbce&#34;&gt;My thoughts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not all rainbows and puppies. This set up is definitely better than my last set up, which consisted mainly of using github pages to host the website and then using &lt;code&gt;HTML&lt;/code&gt; tinkering to create the content. That was hard coded and unsustainable. The templates here make it much easier to change only what I need to. However, the &lt;code&gt;git subtree&lt;/code&gt; workflow is very messy when it goes wrong and I had to &lt;code&gt;rm -rf&lt;/code&gt; some of the earlier repos that got messed up. My setup really doesn&amp;rsquo;t use the version control in the sense of branching and rolling back. It&amp;rsquo;s almost entirely a linear setup, so that works. But I could imagine more heartache if you needed to &lt;code&gt;git revert&lt;/code&gt; some files. Also, I need to consolidate the websites to one site, but that&amp;rsquo;s for a different day.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume Advice</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/resume-tips-newbie/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 21:52:16 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/resume-tips-newbie/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a professional resumé writing expert. But I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting practice updating mine for about 4 years now, since the senior year of high school (when applying to colleges) to now when I&amp;rsquo;m about to look for a real full time job on my way out of college (one more year left).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For reference, my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jeansung/ResumeCollection&#34;&gt;resume collection&lt;/a&gt; my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jeansung/ResumeTemplate&#34;&gt;resume templates&lt;/a&gt;, or my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jeansung/ResumeCollection/raw/master/master_resume/JEANSUNG_RESUME.pdf&#34;&gt;current resume&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is my advice for how to present a summer experience, a project you did on a resume so that all the important information is communicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-you-did:bd80578ac8a5ed369aea3c62f0d851c4&#34;&gt;What you did&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty obvious but you need to write about what you actually do. This is a description of the job that was performed, the piece of software developed or created. For example,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-  Developed educational iPad game for middle school students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;-  Wrote a client library for XYZ API&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-you-did-it:bd80578ac8a5ed369aea3c62f0d851c4&#34;&gt;How you did it&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recruiters, in my experience like seeing what sort of technology was used. It lends legitimacy to your project (are you using the right tool for the job? hopefully!) and backs up your skills section (where did you use your python skills? Oh, this project!). This is about the programming languages used, the tools, technologies, APIs and libraries that your project relies on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;- utilizing Java and JMonkey Game Engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;- with Python and Pandas and Numpy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;- using Google BigQuery and gcs Command Line tools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-it-matters:bd80578ac8a5ed369aea3c62f0d851c4&#34;&gt;Why it matters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cool project, but why? Cool work at your summer job, but why? Why were you necessary? Why were you a worthwhile intern or why was your project interesting? For a job, it&amp;rsquo;s always nice to have something about what your work did to help the company&amp;rsquo;s bottom line? If you have specific numbers, use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;- implemented xyz that saved 2 hours / week of employee time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;- presented research to save company time and resources from unviable path&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;- improved latency from 200ms to 2ms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a project, motivate what you did by showing why the thing you built was useful or explain who could use it. This can also help you think about the usability of your tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;- educational game for middle school students to help them with their math skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;- created xyz with a user interface that reduced complexity of the front end view presented to customers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;- connected X and Y to simplify using tool Z&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;note:bd80578ac8a5ed369aea3c62f0d851c4&#34;&gt;Note&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are writing about a summer job for a tech company, be sure to check with your manager or your HR team about what you can and cannot say about what you did. Especially if you worked for a national lab or signed a really long NDA. Getting a new job is good! Getting sued for breach of contract and leaking trade secrets is not.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to ask for help: Then &amp; Now</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/how-to-ask-tech-q/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 21:52:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/how-to-ask-tech-q/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone at work gave me some helpful advice on Friday and I realized that there is another step in learning how to ask questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first stage in asking questions is the &amp;ldquo;help it&amp;rsquo;s broken&amp;rdquo; stage. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much what it sounds like - something isn&amp;rsquo;t work, it didn&amp;rsquo;t compiled, maybe there was a seg fault, god forbid a merge conflict and you just give up immediately and ask for help. It&amp;rsquo;s what I call the &amp;ldquo;CS 5 on the first day&amp;rdquo; level of asking for help. It&amp;rsquo;s not particularly sophisticated as methods go because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help the person who you&amp;rsquo;re asking for help from understand anything about your problem. It&amp;rsquo;s only really okay if you don&amp;rsquo;t expect to have a hand in fixing the problem or if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how else to ask for help. A slightly more sophisticated version of this: &amp;ldquo;helps it seg faulted or a I got a null pointer exception.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second stage of asking for help is &amp;ldquo;help its broken and I tried x, y, z&amp;rdquo;. This is a  more advanced way of asking questions. For a tutor it&amp;rsquo;s nice because it brings me up to speed oh what has been tried already so I don&amp;rsquo;t waste your time. It&amp;rsquo;s also more advanced because this means you at least tried something. A lot of problems can be solved with a simple print statement, a check for the empty case, some simple debugging. But that&amp;rsquo;s for another post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings me to last Friday. I realized that asking for help at a job is different from asking for help from another fellow software engineer. At tutoring for classes, it is my job to help the students. Even if they don&amp;rsquo;t form the questions well, it&amp;rsquo;s still my job to help. I like helping. Part of my helping is also helping them form the questions. The point is that I&amp;rsquo;m there to help. I work on homework when I don&amp;rsquo;t have questions but for the most part, I know the solution and I know the kinds of problem they are stuck on. But at work it&amp;rsquo;s not the same. Yeah, the team is there when the newbie or the intern (me) needs help. And it definitely is worth it to ask questions instead of struggling for an entire morning on something related to the build that is very team specific. However, the team is composed of software engineers who themselves have stuff to do. So this brings me to the newest type of questions - distilling your question to the essence: What is wrong, and what is the essence of what you don&amp;rsquo;t understand, what you need from the other person. This way, you make sure that you spend their time well and don&amp;rsquo;t waste it asking small question after small question. This is especially important for software engineers who may have their day broken up enough by meetings which makes it hard to do critical thinking that leads to building better software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essence is that you need to think about the other person- how can you help them best help you. Another lesson in empathy. Stay tuned for a post about &amp;ldquo;things I learned being an adult for the summer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Hacks - WIP Edition</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/git-hacks-wip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 22:05:06 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/git-hacks-wip/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s post is about some quick &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; command line tricks if you are doing some work in progress (WIP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scenario: You are working on the &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; branch and then realize you are going to have to test these changes on a bigger scale (perhaps cross repo) and thus new to push your changes to a new branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setup: On master branch, some &lt;code&gt;git add&lt;/code&gt; have been made, no commits yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, remove all the staged files from the master branch. Use &lt;code&gt;git rm --cached&lt;/code&gt; and then either add the file path or the directory path to be removed. You can use &lt;code&gt;git status&lt;/code&gt; to find out what files are not staged yet. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;# Originally, everything is up to date
# but on the wrong branch 
git status 
On branch feature-branch
Your branch is up to date with origin/master
nothing to commit, working directory clean 

# Remove those files 
git rm --cached foo/
git rm --cached bar/foo.java

# Good, ready to be added to another branch
git status 
Changes not staged for commit:
	modified: foo/
Untracked files:
	bar/foo.java
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure to have the &lt;code&gt;--cached&lt;/code&gt; flag because that means that you are removing the file from the git index to reset the tracking but not the actual file from your local file system. You don&amp;rsquo;t want that, because you are about to push these changes to another branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, checkout a new branch. The cool thing is that the current state of files follows you to the current branch. Then, push to remote repo, setting up tracking to be from the origin (usual use case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git checkout -b feature-branch
git add .
git commit -m &amp;quot;Pushing changes to local feature branch&amp;quot;
git push -u origin feature-branch
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last command, &lt;code&gt;git push -u origin feature-branch&lt;/code&gt; sets up the remote branch to track changes from. In the future, you only need to write &lt;code&gt;git push -u feature-branch&lt;/code&gt; and your changes will be pushed to the remote branch of the same name as your local branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sources:9325ce92720b6ac61078754c07b964c3&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1351567/putting-uncommitted-changes-at-master-to-a-new-branch-by-git&#34;&gt;Pushing uncommitted changes to a new branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/7434449/why-use-git-rm-to-remove-a-file-instead-of-rm&#34;&gt;Using git rm &amp;ndash;cached &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The only books I read (anymore)</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/good-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 18:19:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/good-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to read a lot. I grew up reading lots of books from fantasy (all of Harry Potter like many) to cheesy teen romance novels. I even read a book once (okay the entire series) that was written in the style of an IM conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In high school I read the classics - To Kill a Mockingbird, Catch-22, Hamlet, for English, which I liked but only because we had to analyze “deeper meaning” and that was more fun than I knew it could be (but that’s a story for another time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not so much recently. I have to read textbooks during the year - so Physical Chemistry, Linear Algebra and Operating Systems when school is in session. But not really during breaks or for fun. I read articles online and magazines on plane and yes, I guess that does count as reading. But there is something about reading good old fashioned book that I just haven’t done in what seems like forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I got a chance to kickstart the reading habit this summer because of my 40 minute commute (well it’s an hour back in rush hours) by bus. And S let me borrow her old nook. And the library has free e books to rent. Anyways, it came together. And I now remember the only books I can get through anymore fall into 3 categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Cheesy teen romance novels&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;That’s how I got through the 40 minutes on the light rail to the airport&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Books about time management, organization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;My not so secret obsession&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Books that fall under the “common misconception” category See below&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;The last category is interesting because it’s my favorite category. I tell people my favorite book is Catch - 22 which is true but it’s not the type of book I like to read. I like to read books that are stories. Stories about how the way we think is intuitive, which is wrong. These are books that I like to think are born of the Common misconceptions page on Wikipedia.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two such series which I have read and loved are Freakanomics (I’m on the third one) and Malcom Galdwell’s books (all of them). I like them because they are good stories. Stories about how looking at things from a different angle often yields an interesting and meaningful response. And stories about how math is important. And data. And the difference between correlation and causation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I did this</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/why-I-did-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 17:54:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/why-I-did-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Partly because I was curious about newfangled technology and partly because I need to try something out for more than 20 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was eating lunch at work and looking at articles about new technology components- fancy web engines and really pretty interfaces. I’m always enthralled and I always think I should try it but it never gets very far. I start, the supposedly easy to use tool doesn’t compile twenty minutes in or I grow bored and I leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo is the newfangled fancy thing I am trying and it is not easy. The front page is pretty and it lures you in. The defaults work pretty well but then you start to customize it and there are gaps in the documentation. Use &lt;code&gt; {{ delimit .Params.categories “, ” }} &lt;/code&gt; to create comma separated categories. Oh really? Where do I stick this? It looks like it’s a function so I stuck it with the other functions in the layouts (overriding the themes defaults) but it wouldn’t render. I’ve spent about 1 hour on this issue already and it really shouldn’t be this hard. But part of this summer is learning about how to just keep moving forward in the face of all the little details being wrong and not correctly configured. Which I get is how things get done. But I don’t like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted some place to write up cool solutions that I had pieced together from various stack overflow answers, obscure documentation and creative tinkering. A place to feature mini projects I did that weren’t resume or portfolio worthy but could be helpful nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s not really a plan for the blog but the basic layout is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Explanations&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Musings&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thoughts about things. Simply, really. Posts about ideas I stumble across, books I’ve read, things I’ve learned, etc.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Jean’s Journey&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;This is my blog after all. Posts about seasonal routines and goals as well as tech related experiences (like GHC 2015!!)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;A place to feature things I’ve built.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Spotlights and Solutions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;My favorite category. Writeups for problems I’ve fixed and spotlights of cool technologies that solve problems I encounter.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>