<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jeans Journey on Witty Writeups</title>
    <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/categories/jeans-journey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jeans Journey on Witty Writeups</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 21:52:31 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://jeansung.github.io/blog/categories/jeans-journey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2015: Books</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/summer-2015-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 21:52:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/summer-2015-books/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At long last, here is the final count of the books that I managed to read over the summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Author&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Review&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/9627755-isla-and-the-happily-ever-after&#34;&gt;Isla and the Happily Ever After&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Stephanie Perkins&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a classic chick lit novel, the kind I use to read in high school but it was good. It was a good page turner and I got through it quickly, on a train and a plane.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gladwell.com/david-and-goliath/&#34;&gt;David and Goliath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Malcolm Gladwell&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;A new book by one of my favorite authors. This was an excellent read. It&amp;rsquo;s another one of those books that weaves together stories you don&amp;rsquo;t hear about into patterns that don&amp;rsquo;t seem intuitive until they are. It&amp;rsquo;s cleverly woven together, backed by math and logic. I love these books. Also checkout his &lt;a href=&#34;http://gladwell.com/&#34;&gt;other books&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://freakonomics.com/2014/04/02/think-like-a-freak-our-new-book-out-on-may-13/&#34;&gt;Think Like A Freak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Steven D. Levitt, Stephen J. Dubner&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Basically same review as above. I wish I could find more books like these. These are my favorite kind of books. Also checkout the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Freakonomics&#34;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SuperFreakonomics&#34;&gt;second&lt;/a&gt; in the trilogy. I&amp;rsquo;m sad they won&amp;rsquo;t be writing anymore of these.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.npr.org/2014/07/26/334038029/lessons-in-essentialism-getting-more-out-of-life-by-doing-less&#34;&gt;Essentialism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting into this trend recently. Reading a lot of articles online during my lunch break. It&amp;rsquo;s a good read and it was fun to indulge myself before I go back to school where it&amp;rsquo;s less like essentialism and more like &amp;ldquo;do everything ism&amp;rdquo;. Ah, college.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sophiekinsella.co.uk/book_detail.php?b=7&#34;&gt;Shopaholic to the Stars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Sophia Kinsella&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I really only read this because I&amp;rsquo;ve read the previous god knows how many books (7th!!) in this series. It&amp;rsquo;s sort of trashy and sort of cheap, but it&amp;rsquo;s a very quick read.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theghostmap.com/&#34;&gt;The Ghost Map&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Steven Johnson&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I love this story. I did a presentation on the development of the sewage system in London and the 1848 Cholera outbreak. It was an indepth look at all aspects of the disease from more angles than I thought possible. &lt;strong&gt;Definitely&lt;/strong&gt; worth it. It was so great.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/16143347-we-were-liars&#34;&gt;We Were Liars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;E. Lockhart&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;It was a good read. A page turner, and a good book that was aimed at my demographic, for once. It was half a teen romance and half a teen family drama. The mystery in the pages really help keep it going. I got through this book on a train and a plane. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely a enthralling read.  However, retrospectively, I guess I have to agree with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2014/05/11/books/review/we-were-liars-by-e-lockhart.html?_r=0&#34;&gt;New York Times Review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gettingthingsdone.com/&#34;&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;David Allen&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;ve read this before. It&amp;rsquo;s good, and I like organizational books, but the system is a bit complex and I think it would work better with a consistent work schedule rather than a busy and every shifting school schedule. People say to treat your job like a 9-5 but my job is more like a 10am-12am. Or something like that. Ahh, clinic.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;GRE Math, Verbal prep&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Kaplan&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;This is because I decided for some reason it would be a good idea to sign up for and then study for and then take the August GRE. Oh silly me. It was fine. Just a long test. Luckily, I remembered most of my middle school and high school math. Shame there&amp;rsquo;s no calculus.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to ask for help: Then &amp; Now</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/how-to-ask-tech-q/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 21:52:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/how-to-ask-tech-q/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Someone at work gave me some helpful advice on Friday and I realized that there is another step in learning how to ask questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first stage in asking questions is the &amp;ldquo;help it&amp;rsquo;s broken&amp;rdquo; stage. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much what it sounds like - something isn&amp;rsquo;t work, it didn&amp;rsquo;t compiled, maybe there was a seg fault, god forbid a merge conflict and you just give up immediately and ask for help. It&amp;rsquo;s what I call the &amp;ldquo;CS 5 on the first day&amp;rdquo; level of asking for help. It&amp;rsquo;s not particularly sophisticated as methods go because it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help the person who you&amp;rsquo;re asking for help from understand anything about your problem. It&amp;rsquo;s only really okay if you don&amp;rsquo;t expect to have a hand in fixing the problem or if you don&amp;rsquo;t know how else to ask for help. A slightly more sophisticated version of this: &amp;ldquo;helps it seg faulted or a I got a null pointer exception.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second stage of asking for help is &amp;ldquo;help its broken and I tried x, y, z&amp;rdquo;. This is a  more advanced way of asking questions. For a tutor it&amp;rsquo;s nice because it brings me up to speed oh what has been tried already so I don&amp;rsquo;t waste your time. It&amp;rsquo;s also more advanced because this means you at least tried something. A lot of problems can be solved with a simple print statement, a check for the empty case, some simple debugging. But that&amp;rsquo;s for another post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings me to last Friday. I realized that asking for help at a job is different from asking for help from another fellow software engineer. At tutoring for classes, it is my job to help the students. Even if they don&amp;rsquo;t form the questions well, it&amp;rsquo;s still my job to help. I like helping. Part of my helping is also helping them form the questions. The point is that I&amp;rsquo;m there to help. I work on homework when I don&amp;rsquo;t have questions but for the most part, I know the solution and I know the kinds of problem they are stuck on. But at work it&amp;rsquo;s not the same. Yeah, the team is there when the newbie or the intern (me) needs help. And it definitely is worth it to ask questions instead of struggling for an entire morning on something related to the build that is very team specific. However, the team is composed of software engineers who themselves have stuff to do. So this brings me to the newest type of questions - distilling your question to the essence: What is wrong, and what is the essence of what you don&amp;rsquo;t understand, what you need from the other person. This way, you make sure that you spend their time well and don&amp;rsquo;t waste it asking small question after small question. This is especially important for software engineers who may have their day broken up enough by meetings which makes it hard to do critical thinking that leads to building better software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essence is that you need to think about the other person- how can you help them best help you. Another lesson in empathy. Stay tuned for a post about &amp;ldquo;things I learned being an adult for the summer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Things I learned searching for jobs.</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/fall2015_jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2015 18:19:43 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/fall2015_jobs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I did this</title>
      <link>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/why-I-did-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 17:54:38 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jeansung.github.io/blog/post/why-I-did-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Partly because I was curious about newfangled technology and partly because I need to try something out for more than 20 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was eating lunch at work and looking at articles about new technology components- fancy web engines and really pretty interfaces. I’m always enthralled and I always think I should try it but it never gets very far. I start, the supposedly easy to use tool doesn’t compile twenty minutes in or I grow bored and I leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hugo is the newfangled fancy thing I am trying and it is not easy. The front page is pretty and it lures you in. The defaults work pretty well but then you start to customize it and there are gaps in the documentation. Use &lt;code&gt; {{ delimit .Params.categories “, ” }} &lt;/code&gt; to create comma separated categories. Oh really? Where do I stick this? It looks like it’s a function so I stuck it with the other functions in the layouts (overriding the themes defaults) but it wouldn’t render. I’ve spent about 1 hour on this issue already and it really shouldn’t be this hard. But part of this summer is learning about how to just keep moving forward in the face of all the little details being wrong and not correctly configured. Which I get is how things get done. But I don’t like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted some place to write up cool solutions that I had pieced together from various stack overflow answers, obscure documentation and creative tinkering. A place to feature mini projects I did that weren’t resume or portfolio worthy but could be helpful nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s not really a plan for the blog but the basic layout is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Category&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Explanations&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Musings&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Thoughts about things. Simply, really. Posts about ideas I stumble across, books I’ve read, things I’ve learned, etc.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Jean’s Journey&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;This is my blog after all. Posts about seasonal routines and goals as well as tech related experiences (like GHC 2015!!)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Projects&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;A place to feature things I’ve built.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Spotlights and Solutions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;My favorite category. Writeups for problems I’ve fixed and spotlights of cool technologies that solve problems I encounter.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>